《越狱》第四季 第九集
Prison.Break.S04E09
《越狱》  前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break.
你要"锡拉"做什么
What do you want with Scylla?
和你一样  打垮"公司"
Same thing you want: bring down the Company.
我们需要那几页
We need the pages.
我们一起合作吗
Are we partners?
是的
Partners.
你哥哥跟我说了你流鼻血的事
So your brother told me about your nosebleeds.
我很好
I'm fine.
你看起来可不好
You don't look fine.
对不起
Sorry.
引以为戒吧
Consider this a warning.
林肯  倒回去
Linc, pull back!
是个圈套
It's a trap!
快走  林肯
Come on, Linc!
等一下
Hang on!
你没事吧  你中枪了
You all right?! Damn, you're hit!
好了  好了
All right, all right.
你会有机会收拾他的  退后
You'll get your shot, now back off!
他们是想拿我的卡
This is an attempt on my card.
接下来你想怎么办
How do you want to proceed?
我要转移它
I want it moved.
转移"锡拉"
Move Scylla.
现在
Now!
告诉将军你把我们都干掉了
Now, tell the General you killed us.
否则  我的手可不会歇着
Otherwise, my hand, it ain't going to get tired.
我觉得你的嘴该歇歇了
I just hope your mouth gets tired.
很搞笑
That's funny.
走吧  老兄  走吧
Come on, buddy, come on.
够了  我们走吧  林肯
Enough already, come on, Linc.
现在相信我了吧
Believe me now?
打他是没有用的  林肯
Beating him isn't going to work, Lincoln.
你的方法也用过了
You tried your way.
我们要让克兰兹将军相信怀特已经把我们解决了
We want General Krantz to think Wyatt took us out.
就算你把他打到给将军打电话
Even if you do beat him to make the call to general.
你觉得一个训练有素的军人
you don't think a trained military veteran
听不出他话里的恐惧吗
is going to hear the fear in his voice?
他们会知道他是被强迫的
They're going to know he was coerced.
对付他要多点时间
Yeah,well.I need some more time with him.
我明白  林肯  但是他神志不清的话也不能打电话
I hear you, Linc, but he can't make the call if he's unconscious.
不管我们怎么做
However we do it,
我们最好快点从怀特那里得到我们想要的
we better get what we need from Wyatt soon,
马宏可等不及了
because Mahone ain't going to wait.
我要找到那个杀我儿子的贱人
I'm trying to find the son of a bitch who killed my kid!
丽莎  情况如何
Lisa, what are we looking at?
初步估计转移"锡拉"大概要三天
Initial estimate is three days to complete the move of Scylla.
我不能接受
Unacceptable.
请听我说  这可不像把一台电脑
Respectfully, this is not as simple as unplugging
从一间房挪到另一间房那么简单
a laptop and moving it to another room.
"锡拉"里的数据太复杂了
The data on Scylla is too delicate.
我不想听理由
I don't want excuses.
我只关心  它能否妥善转移以及是否现在就转移
All I care is that it's done right and done right now.
我明白这很紧急  但也要三天时间
I understand the urgency, but it will take three days.
请允许我说几句  我觉得
And if I may speak freely, I think it's a mistake
把"锡拉"转移到拉文罗克地堡
to move Scylla to the Raven Rock bunker
而放弃对我们来说最安全的洛城
when the Los Angeles facility
是一个错误
is one of the most secure ones we have.
对我们来说最安全的地方
The most secure location we have
就是不为人知的地方
is the one they don't know about.
长官
Sir...
还是没有怀特的消息
Still no word from Wyatt.
他只用"公司"提供的电话
He only uses the company-issued cell,
我们追踪不到他
so we can't track him.
我们无法确定
We have no way of confirming
他是否完成了任务
if he successfully completed his operation.
继续联系
Keep calling him!
准备一份新闻稿
And draft a press release,
照片  犯罪记录
photographs, criminal records,
所有关于斯科菲尔德  布伦斯等人的全部资料
everything we have on Scofield, Burrows, all of them.
告诉媒体的朋友  我要他们
Tell our friends in the media I want them
在晚间新闻和早报里都报导
to saturate the evening news and the morning papers.
我要让他们不能
I want it impossible for them
大摇大摆的走在洛城的街道上
to walk down the streets of Los Angeles without being spotted.
我猜我们还没在他身上
I assume we haven't made much progress
得到任何进展
with our friend over there?
有什么建议吗
Any suggestions?
要不我们和他谈谈
How about we talk to him?
好啊  要不要给他点牛奶和饼干
Great, want to give him some milk and cookies while you're at it?
不是
No.
随便聊聊怎么样
How about just some nice conversation?
他们就叫个护士
So they sent Florence Nightingale
来让我乖乖合作
to get me all ready to cooperate.
实际上   不管你做了什么  我是来帮你的
Actually, I'm here to help you, despite what you've done.
因为我还是医生  而你是囚犯
Because I'm still a doctor and you're a prisoner.
你想要救我
You're going to save me?
唐・赛尔夫带了个箱子来
Don Self has a metal case out there
我不知道里面有什么
and I don't know what's in it.
我猜你也不会想知道
I imagine you don't want to find out,
所以  我想我们要是谈谈
so I figure if you and I had a talk...
你会给我一线生机
You'd make me see the light.
你要是不给将军打电话  你就死定了
If you don't call the General, you're as good as dead.
我早经历过很多生不如死的事  医生
I've already been a lot of things worse than dead in my life, Doctor.
你还是找个好点的理由来威胁我
You better have more than that to threaten me with.
放心  迈克尔  她没事的
Come on, Mike, she's okay.
他是个职业杀手
He's a professional killer.
不用担心  他已经被拷起来了
Don't worry, he's locked up.
我们走吧
Let's go.
快点  我们走吧
Come on, let's go!
你想怎么处理罗兰的尸体
So what'd you do with Roland's body?
罗兰
Roland?
他的资料已经全改了
He's been, uh, reconfigured
而且埋在一个长眠之地
and given a permanent resting place.
太好了  你走的时候顺便
Good. Take his bowling shirts
把他的衣物和他的垃圾也带走
and the rest of his crap with you when you leave.
算了吧  林肯  人都死了
Come on Linc, the guy died.
他出卖了我们  死有余辜  贝里克
He died a punk! He ratted us out, Bellick.
各位  我们先处理眼前的事
You guys, you deal with the matter at hand.
假设这几张纸是正确的
Assuming these pages are correct,
我们也无从考证它们是不是真的
and there's no way of knowing that they actually are...
我们从地下走廊  通过锅炉房到这
we follow this basement hallway through the boiler room to here.
这里是往上走的爬梯
There's some kind of elevated walkway.
我们顺着走到底
We follow that to the end,
这样我们就涵盖了大部分
and we've covered most of the distance
从伽特到"公司"总部间的距离
between GATE and the Company's headquarters.
走廊尽头的是什么东西
What's this thing at the end of the walkway?
我也不知道  惠斯勒用X做了个标记
I don't know-- Whistler marked it with an "X"
我想可能是面墙或大的障碍物
so I'm thinking it's some kind of wall or serious impediment.
所以我们要下去做好准备
That's why we're going down there prepared.
工具  电焊  锤子
Tools, thermal lances, sledgehammers...
就算我们穿过了墙
Okay, so we get through that wall...
另一边是什么
what's on the other side?
我还不知道
Again, I don't know.
因为剩下的几页在格雷琴手里
It's because Gretchen has the rest of the pages.
但是一旦我们通过这个地方
But once we're through this location,
除非她把几页纸给我们  否则就无法前进
we can't go any further until she gives them back.
她到底耍什么诡计
What's her game in all this?
如果她想把"公司"搞垮
I mean, if she wants the Company to go down,
她就应该把几页纸给我们
she should just give us the pages.
只要时机成熟
Look, we're going to deal with Gretchen
我们就解决格雷琴
when the time is right, okay?
你们要
You guys need
去伽特开始准备
to go to GATE and get started.
我留下来看着怀特
I'm going to stay here with Wyatt
确保从他嘴里套有用的东西
and make sure we get what we need.
从现在开始不能乱串
No more dawdlin' now.
走快点
Move your ass.
快点  先生们  快点
High gear, gentlemen, high gear.
我老板随时可能会来
My boss will be here any minute.
我想我不用重申谨慎行事至关重要
I assume I don't have to mention that discretion is paramount.
换句话说  "沉默"是金
In other words, silence is golden.
你只要确保在办公室里呆着
You just make sure you stay in your office
别让别人进来
and you keep other people out.
我会呆在舒适
Oh, I'll stay in my nice,
凉快的办公室里的  小白脸
air-conditioned office, Pretty.
你现在可以爬你的小洞里去了
And you can crawl down into your little hole now.
快
Go ahead.
快  爬吧
Go ahead, crawl.
科尔  这里到底出什么事了
Cole? What the hell is going on here?
怀特先生  你回来了
Mr. White, are you back already?
你好吗
How are you?
很好  直到我收到一封安德鲁・布劳努
Fine, until I found a resignation fax
发来的辞职传真
waiting for me from Andrew Blauner.
辞职信
A resignation?
对  打电话也不接
Yeah, I can't get him on the phone,
我打给他未婚妻
I reached out to his fiancee,
她也不知道没有他的消息
she hasn't seen or heard from him.
她非常担心
She's worried sick.
他可能就是喝大了
He's probably on a bit of a bender,
睡在什么地方了
just sleeping it off somewhere.
布劳努可是名童子军
Blauner? He's a Boy Scout.
这不合逻辑  科尔
None of this makes any sense, Cole.
不过我告诉你
But I'll tell you what,
我会查清楚的
I'm going to look into it.
有需要我帮忙的地方  就告诉我
Let me know if I can be of any assistance.
早上好
Good morning.
帮忙
Assistance...
那是什么声音
What is that sound?
喂
Yeah?
我希望能有个愉快的早晨
I hope you're having a lovely enjoyable morning,
因为你不在的时候
because while you are nowhere to be found,
这边已经在调查
there is sleuthing going on here
安德鲁・布劳努的下落了
regarding the whereabouts of one Mr. Andrew Blauner.
还有吗
And?
如果我卷进这起凶杀案的话
And if I'm going down for this little homicide,
我可不会一个人背黑锅
I ain't going alone.
我们肯定是形影不离的
We're going together like traffic and weather.
放松点  好吗
Relax, okay?
他们绝对找不到我放尸体的地方
They'll never find the body where I put it.
斯科菲尔德和布伦斯现在在哪
Now, where are Scofield and Burrows?
正在履行他们的承诺
Just doing their end of the bargain.
顺便问一下  你到底在干嘛
Which begs the question, what the hell are you doing?
我
Me?
我准备去会一个人
I'm getting ready for a meeting.
你朋友一直打电话给你
So, your friends have been calling a lot.
他们一定在想你到哪儿去了
They must be wondering where you are.
没错
That's right.
他们在怀疑  而他们怀疑得越久
They're wondering, and the longer they do,
你们就越危险
the more danger you're in.
打电话给将军  照他们的话说
Call the General, and say what they want you to say.
然后呢  你们会放我走吗
And what? You'll let me go?
不会  但唐・赛尔夫能确保
No, but Don Self will make sure
你免于死刑
that you spend the rest of your life
下半辈子悠闲自在
in a decent facility without the death penalty.
无论如何
Either way,
无论我打不打这通电话
if I make the call or not,
我都会死
I'm dead.
你心里明白的很
You know that.
我们都清楚  你作为一名医生
And we both know that you, as a doctor,
不会容许这种事情发生
won't let that happen.
所以  不如
So, please,
我们一起想个
let's you and I figure a way
互惠互利的解决办法
out of this mess that works for everybody.
-坐好  -别挡路
Sit your ass down! Get out of my way!
别 别这样
Out! Out!
不然我会把你按在桌子上的
I will cuff your ass to that table, okay?
我知道这很痛苦
All right, I know this is hard.
我也知道你想干什么
And I know what you want to do.
可是我们正在努力做事
Okay, but I'm trying to do something here
你必须接受现实
and you need to deal with that reality.
你有失去孩子吗
Have you lost a kid?
我失去过
Yeah, I did, too.
我老婆当时怀孕
My wife was pregnant.
她有并发症  而那个庸医不会处理
And there were complications and the doctor messed up.
而她
And she...
他们都
And they both...
他们都死了
They didn't make it.
行了吧  我感同身受
Okay? So I understand.
如果你是我  你会怎么做
What would you do if you were me
如果坐在那里的就是那个庸医
and that doctor was right there?
你会怎样
What would you do?
我也不知道我会怎样
I don't know what I would do.
听着  我向你保证
Look, I'm giving you my word.
一旦时机成熟  我绝对不会阻拦你
When the time is right, I won't stand in your way.
到时候你也拦不住我
When the time is right I won't let you.
行  行
Okay. Okay.
你们看到马宏看怀特的样子吗
Did you see the way  Mahone was looking at Wyatt?
那家伙很伤心
The guy is hurting.
不是伤心那么简单  简直就是煎熬
It was more than just hurting, that's pain.
我从来没有那么在意一件事
I never cared about anything like that.
看看我这辈子
I look at what I've done with my life,
在福克斯河监狱作威作福  捞钱
beating on cons at Fox River, chasing money,
努力离开监狱
trying to keep my own ass out of prison.
这就是你说的那条小路吗
This the pathway you talking about?
根据地图
According to the map,
这条路几乎有整个中庭那么长
this runs almost the length of that courtyard.
它应该直接通向"公司"总部的下方
It should put us directly beneath Company headquarters.
嘘  听
Shh, listen.
又是这种声音
There it is again.
那是什么声音  斯科菲尔德
What's that noise, Scofield?
不知道
I don't know.
那么我们都清楚  我们要爬上楼梯
Okay, just so we're clear, we get to go up that ladder
去往那个不明声音的来源地
towards the noise that we don't know what it is.
如果走运的话  我们就基本能
But if we're lucky, we get to basically just
潜进"公司"
walk smack into the Company?
没错
Sounds about right.
你要上去吗
You up for it?
当然  紧随你后
Oh, yeah, after you.
我跟坐在那边的
I am no different than that man
那个想杀我的人没什么不同
over there... who wants to kill me.
亚历山大・马宏是被迫为"公司"卖命
Alexander Mahone was forced to do things by the Company,
我也一样
and so was I.
但我认识一些人
But I know people.
在政府做事的人
People in government.
他们能帮你和迈克尔
People that can help you and Michael.
我可以给你一个电话号码
I can give you a phone number.
可以安排一下
Arrangements can be made.
你只要相信我
All you have to do is trust me
一切都可以结束
and this will all be over.
已经结束了
It is over.
怀特有布劳努的新消息吗
Has, um, White had anything new to say about Blauner?
没有  但他可能会有
No, but he might.
普发先生
Mr. Pfeiffer?
正是本人
That would be moi.
康纳・莫拉侦探
Detective Conor Mara.
我想跟你谈谈安德鲁・布劳努的事
I was hoping I could talk to you about Andrew Blauner.
当然可以
Of course.
太好了
Great.
从这下去
It's down this way.
找到了
This is it!
这就是那种声音的来源
This is where the sound was coming from.
洛城其中一条供水的主水管
One of the main conduit pipes for the LA water supply.
每秒3万加仑的水
30,000 gallons of water rushing through this very spot.
-流经这里  -那完了
Every second. Oh, great.
有其他路可以绕过这家伙吗
There's got to be some other way to get around it,
其他通道什么的
some other pathway or something.
没有  我们从唯一一条通道下来
No, we took the only pathway down
直接来到这里
and it leads right here.
从上面越过怎么样
How about over it?
我们不能冒险太接近地面挖隧道
We can't risk tunneling too close to the surface.
那怎么办
What do we do?
挖
We dig.
不瞒您说
Truth be told, uh,
布劳努先生还不算真正失踪
Mr. Blauner isn't officially a missing person,
但他的未婚妻有个堂妹在市长办公室工作
but his fiancee has a cousin at the mayor's office
所以  就是这样
so, here we are.
就是这样
Here we are.
但并不是说
Hey, that's not to say though that there
就没有可担心的事
aren't some things that concern me.
是吗  比如呢
Really? Such as?
怀特办公室收到的传真
Well, the fax that came into White's office
是在一家复印店传的
came from a copy shop,
但布劳努家里有传真机
but Blauner had a fax machine at his house.
还有呢
Okay.
他辞职大约半小时后
And about a half hour after he resigned,
有人看到他的车从伽特车库驶出
his car was seen leaving the GATE garage.
司机的身份现在无法确认
Now, the driver couldn't be identified,
但很明确驾驶员
but it appeared as though a woman's hands
是位女性
were seen gripping the steering wheel.
容我打断一下
Let me stop you right there.
我一直觉得布劳努先生
It always seemed to me that Mr. Blauner was,
怎么说比较恰当呢
how can I put this delicately,
是个"贱"客
um, a swordsman.
明白我的意思吗
You know what I mean?
说实话  不懂
Actually, I don't.
他可是到处播种
He might be dipping his snout into a different trough,
而她未婚妻却蒙在鼓里
and the fiancee is none the wiser.
但据其他同事所说
From what I've, uh, heard about him from his other co-workers,
这似乎不太可能
that doesn't sound too likely.
冒昧问一下  那个敲击声是怎么回事
If you don't mind me asking, what is that banging noise?
那是
That's, uh...
管道问题
it's trouble with the pipes.
是管道松了  以前有点震动
You know, they loosened up, it was a moderate quake
现在比以前震的更厉害了
and now they shake more than the trembler itself.
普发先生  有人告诉我
Mr. Pfeiffer, uh, some people here
你和布劳努有隙
have told me that you and Blauner didn't get along.
你能否说下这个问题
Would you mind talking to me a little bit about that?
几年前  我和一个搭档也用这招对付
A few years ago, a partner of mine did this same move
在新墨西哥边界抓到的
against an enemy combatant we picked up
犯人  这家伙嘴巴很紧
at the New Mexico border-- this guy didn't want to talk,
他什么都说不知道
he didn't know anything.
当时很有用  现在也应该行
It worked then, it should work now.
你给我们弄回来的救护车还在外面吗
Is that ambulance you got us still out back?
是的
Yeah.
加油  伙计  我当年追捕你们半天
Hey, come on, pal, I got almost a decade on you
都不见我喘半口气
and you don't see me sucking air.
布拉德  我中弹了
I got shot, Brad.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
兄弟们  没进展啊
Guys, we ain't making any progress here.
水泥层下只有花岗岩
There's nothing beneath this cement but granite.
用手提钻是穿不过去的
We couldn't get through it with a jackhammer.
也许我们该回仓库看看
Maybe we should go back to the warehouse,
另找出路
find another way.
没有其他出路  只有这里
There is no other way. This is it!
这就是计划所向  只能从这条路找"锡拉"
This is where the plans lead; this is our way to Scylla.
什么
What?
这排泄管里有数百万加仑的水
We got millions of gallons of water in this drain pipe.
我们下不去  也越不过去
We can't go under it, we can't go over it.
我知道
I know.
或许我们能穿过去
Maybe we can go through it.
松了
It's loose!
好了  林肯  这应该管用
All right, Linc, this ought to do it.
我搞定之后  我们有多长时间
After I'm done, how much time we got?
不多
Not a lot.
小心点
Be careful.
你也是
You, too.
我小时候  养了只公猫叫鲁弗斯
When I was a little boy, I had an old tomcat named Rufus.
它很擅长抓老鼠
He was a good mouser.
尖牙利爪  很彪悍的猫
Tough as nails, solid feline all around.
有一天  我在大卖场外面
One day, I bring home this little kitty
捡回一只小猫咪
from a giveaway box outside the Pic 'N Save.
老鲁弗斯一点也喜欢它
Old Rufus didn't like that one bit.
它耸起背  像响尾蛇一样丝丝叫
He arched his back, hissed like a rattlesnake
想弹簧刀一般伸出爪子
and sprang out his claws like a switchblade.
你知道
You know,
这小猫咪没做错什么
That new little kitty didn't do nothing wrong
只是个新来的
but be new.
我现在也是如此
Now, that's all I did.
我是新来的  布劳努是
I was being new, and Blauner was being
那只划清自己领地的老猫
this old tomcat spraying his territory.
但我不是针对他
Now, I don't hold that against him.
如果他不这么做  我倒会怀疑他人格有问题
If he didn't protect his turf I'd question his character.
但除了他的嫉妒以外
But aside from a little jealousy on his part,
我们之间就像纸一样薄
our issues were as thin as tissues.
我向你保证
I assure you that.
侦探  我把布劳努的行程安排
Detective, I pulled Blauner's travel schedule
-按你的要求打出来了  -谢谢
as per your request. Thank you.
这是怎么回事
Uh, what's this?
先生  我们得出去
Uh, sir, uh, we need to step out
拿一些做架子的角板
for a few more bracket-joints for the shelving.
没问题
Uh, all right, yeah.
但你们出去吃吃喝喝
But I ain't paying you to stop for, uh,
我可不会付钱给你们  快去快回
a coffee and donuts, so get back here toot sweet.
等等我  曼纽尔
Hey, wait up, Manuel.
我雇了几个人  当然是自己掏腰包
I hired some men, uh, out of my own pocket of course,
来修整一下
to, uh, add some built-in uh,
我的储物室  希望你别介意
uh, storage in my closet-- I hope you don't mind.
没问题
Nah.
这是他的每月细目
Here's the monthly breakdown of where he traveled...
你要跟我谈吗
You're gonna talk to me now?
我  不
Me? No.
我们没什么好谈的
We're done talking...
但你还得说
But you're not.
他们都死了  结束了
They are all dead. It's over.
一切都可以结束
This will all be over.
完了
It's over.
他们都死了  他们都死了
They are dead. They are all dead.
结束了
It's over.
我要把这个拿走
I'm going to take this.
赛尔夫
Self...
你们能回避吗
Can you take a walk?
可以
Yeah.
走吧  莎拉  我们该走了
Come on, Sara, we should go.
我们出去吧
Let's go outside.
我儿子的尸检显示他
My son's autopsy report said that he'd...
他中了两枪
that he'd been shot twice.
一枪在肚子上
Once in the stomach...
为什么
Why, man?
为什么  就为了恐吓我妻子
Why?! Just to terrify my wife?!
五分钟后
And then a full five minutes later,
打在
right in the...
你也要承受一下
You too will suffer.
当
And when...
当你也无法承受疼痛时
and when you can't stand the pain anymore,
你就要为我打个电话
you'll make a phone call for me.
斯科菲尔德说酷刑没有用
You know, Scofield said that torture wouldn't work
因为将军会从你的声音中听出恐惧
because the General would hear the fear in your voice.
但事实上
But the thing is...
我正是要让电话那头的人
...I want the person on the other end
从你的声音中听到
of my call to hear the fear
恐惧
in your voice.
先生  这是新闻稿
Press release, sir.
简而言之  就是说福科斯河监狱的
In short, it sets forth that members
八个逃犯和帮凶
of the Fox River Eight and their accomplices
都还活着并就在洛城
are alive and well in Los Angeles.
你去哪了
Where have you been?
他们都死了
They are all dead.
-都结束了  -干得好
It's over. Good work.
你的报酬会放在约定的地方
Your payment will be left where we arranged.
这个已经没必要了
This is no longer necessary.
别轻举妄动
Go ahead.
秘密入口的
The access code
密码还是
to the covert entrance
你两个女儿的生日
is still both your daughters' birthdays.
所有人都出去
Everyone leave us alone.
我说
I said
所有人都出去
everyone leave us alone.
不会有事的
It's okay.
她不会伤害我
She won't hurt me.
丽莎
Lisa...
我就知道你会回家
I knew you'd come home.
你怎么挺得住
So, how are you holding up, you know,
没有LJ和大家陪在身边
not being with LJ and all?
没什么  他是个好孩子  他会照顾好自己
Good, he's a smart kid. He can look after himself.
我能看出来你很爱他
I can see it, how much you love him.
我还很小  我爸就去世了
My dad died when I was a little kid.
但他是个好父亲
But he was a good father.
我们还是集中精力完成任务吧
Let's just focus and get this thing done, all right?
迈克尔说手动控制
Michael said the manual override
应该就在主管道附近
should be somewhere near the main conduit.
你觉得这个像主管道吗
This look like the main conduit to you?
有办法弄明白
One way to find out.
你觉得这个像吗
That look like it to you?
像
Looks like it.
把它点着
Fire it up.
好了  我们走吧
All right, let's get out of here.
快点  哥们
Hurry up, bro!
就快好了 兄弟
Almost done, buddy.
好了  把它挪回去
All right, ease it back.
搞定了
It worked.
我们有多长时间
How long we got?
不清楚
I don't know.
千万人的水源被切断
Water cut off to thousands of people.
政府会在一个小时左右抢修
The city will probably have that taken care of in about an hour,
意味着我们有60分钟
which means we've got... 60 minutes
做90分钟的工作
to do 90 minutes worth of work.
否则我们就得不到"锡拉"
Or we don't get to Scylla.
怎么了  老兄
What's wrong, papi?
迈克
Mike.
迈克尔  迈克尔
Michael! Michael!
怎么了  兄弟
What's wrong, papi?!
兄弟  说话啊
Papi, talk to me!
你怎么了  说话啊
What's wrong?! Talk to me!
迈克尔
Michael!
迈克尔  你怎么了
Michael, what's wrong?!
想喝水吗
You want some water?
我没事
I'm okay.
兄弟  你现在背负过重
You're a lot of things right now, my friend,
而却没有背负"没事"
and okay ain't one of them.
你知道  我可能不是最聪明的人
You know, I may not be the smartest guy,
但我听到了
but I hear things.
莎拉和你哥哥
Sara and your brother
谈过有关你的身体健康的问题
have been talking about you not feeling well or something.
听着  我只是  只是说说
Look, I'm just, I'm just saying.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
所以  请你
So, please, just, uh...
帮我瞒着
...cover for me.
没问题
You got it.
事实上  格雷琴  我比你更了解你自己
Truth is, Gretchen, I know you better than you know yourself.
你一直这么跟我说
So you keep telling me.
我初次见你时  你才20岁
When I first met you, you were a 20 year old girl
由于心理评估失败
who'd just been dumped by the Wheeling Police Academy
你被惠灵警官学院开除了
for failing her psych evaluation.
但那些佛吉尼亚老脑筋
But where those good old West Virginia boys
只能看出一种具有
could only see an emotional disconnect
反社会倾向的情绪反常
with traces of sociopathic tendencies,
我看到的是一个能
I saw a Machiavellian streak
让失败成为不可能的足智多谋的人
that would make failure an impossibility.
我只能让怀特那么做
I had to let Wyatt do what he did
因为我想知道
because I needed to know...
是否我的斗牛犬已得知惠斯勒
...what my little bulldog may have known
以及他想得到关锡拉的计划
about Whistler and his plans for Scylla.
我说过我什么也不知道
I told you that I knew nothing.
你应该相信我
You should have believed me.
我知道你从不义气用事
I knew you'd never take it personally,
因为从你成为我的左右手开始
because you are, and have been
你就是  也一直是
ever since I took you under my wing...
我的女人
...my girl.
My girl.
最敏感的神经末梢就在这里
The most sensitive nerve endings are right here.
这就是为什么针灸医生都会避免
That's why acupuncturists avoid placing needles
在任何接近这个位置用针  因为
anywhere near them because opening up
指尖的神经末端
the nerve endings in the fingertip--
就算只刺到一点
even a little pinprick--
都能引起极大的灼热痛楚
can result in quite a painful hot flash.
所以一根5英寸长的针
So a five inch needle
插入一指的长度
being driven up the length of the finger...
能让你体内感觉被火燃烧一般
...can make your insides feel like they're on fire.
生理学的另一方面说
Another fact of physiology,
当人体无法承受极端的压迫时会休克
the human body when in extreme duress begins to shut down.
大脑活动减弱  心率也会下降
Brain activity decreases and your heart rate slows
直到你再也感觉不到疼痛
until you just can't feel the pain anymore.
这就是心电图和电击的作用
And that's where the heart monitor and the battery come in.
因为当你的心率降到50以下
'Cause when your heart rate dips below 50,
电击就会给你一个苏醒的信号
that battery will give you a wake-up call,
避免你的身体休克
preventing your body from shutting down.
你才能感受到任何一丁点的
And then you will feel every ounce...
疼痛
of the pain.
到时候你会求着让我打电话
And that's when you're going to beg me to make the phone call.
有什么可以帮你吗
What can I do you for?
我在你的销售报告里找到
I... I found some more inconsistencies
一些矛盾的地方
in your sales reports.
听着
Listen up here.
你的电脑可不可以
From that little computer of yours,
读取伽特的数据
can you access into GATE's records?
如果用管理员身份登陆的话
If I access the network as an administrator,
我能以非pdf格式浏览文件
I can see the files in a non-PDF format.
我不知道什么意思  但我认为你可以办到
I don't know what that means, but I assume it was a yes.
所以随你怎么敲键盘
So you let your fingers do the walking across that keyboard
把我的销售报告拿给我
and you get me my sales records.
你弄伤我的手臂了
You are hurting my arm.
最好别让我伤害其他部位
And don't make me hurt any more of you.
现在就去
Now, go.
做的好
That's good work.
给
Here.
我要你测量下这个洞
I need you to measure this hole.
在对面的墙上打个同等大小的洞
And then make one of the same size in the wall opposite.
怎么弄
How?
你有系腰带吧
You got a belt?
好了
Okay.
在水再次灌满水管之前
We have less than 30 minutes
我们还有不到半小时时间
until this pipe is flooded with water again.
接受现实是很重要的  怀特
Acceptance is important, Wyatt.
我必须接受我儿子已经死了
I had to accept that my son is gone.
而你也必须接受你的生命
And you have to accept that your life,
你所剩无几的生命
your very, very short life-span ahead of you
将充满无法忍受的疼痛
is just going to be filled with agonizing pain.
直到你按我的要求去做
At least until you do what I've asked of you.
到那时
And then...
痛苦将会离你而去
then the pain will go away.
我们快没时间了
We're running out of time!
-不会吧  -怎么了
- Man.  - What's wrong?
这该死的东西居然空了
The stupid thing is empty!
那么
All right.
我进去吧
I'm coming in.
老兄  你不行了
You can't do this, bro.
赶紧干完再说
Just finish it.
喂
Hello?
是我
It's me.
怎么了
What's going on?
有人要告诉你一些事
Somebody needs to tell you something.
用她的姓称呼她
You call her by her first name.
潘姆
Pam...
我很抱歉
I'm... sorry.
一切都结束了
It's over.
我爱你
And I love you.
I love you.
这东西太沉了
This thing is heavy!
太好了  苦力活干完了你们才来
Sure, show up when all the hard work is done.
好了  松后点
All right, ease it back.
我们听电台说
We heard on the radio
水利部门会在10分钟内恢复供水
that DWP is going to have the water running in 10 minutes.
你没事吧
You all right?
管子太重了
The sleeve is too heavy
很难塞过排水管
to just slide it through the pipe.
必须有2个人进去
Two of us are going to have to go inside
引它穿过另一个洞口
and guide it through that other hole.
水流随时可能从排水管冲过来
That pipe can flood at any time.
我上
I'll do it.
我也上
I'll go, too.
不  让我来
No, I'll go.
优等生  并非冒犯
Oh, no offense, college boy,
但这大家伙太重了
but this sucker's heavy.
你得再强壮点才行
You're going to need a little bulk down there.
好吧
All right.
你们把它推过另一边时
Use this to brace the sleeve
用这个支撑水管
when you pull it through to the other side.
然后  我们一起离开这里  好吗
And Let's get the hell out of there, all right?
艾咪还好吗
How's Emmy?
我来这不是听你
I didn't come here to listen to you
假装关心她  或关心我
Pretend to care about her...or me.
我来此是要告诉你  我是现在是空闲探员
I came here to tell you that I'm a free agent now.
我们经营的集团知道我还活着且可以雇用
The community we run with know that I'm alive and available.
我可以像为你卖命一样为他们卖命
I can just as easily work for one of them as I can for you.
所以问题在于  你出价多少
So the question is, what's your offer?
实际上  你的问题是
Actually, the question for you is
何必去其他地方呢
why would you want to go anywhere else?
现在不是记仇的时候  格雷琴
It's not a time for grudges, Gretchen.
是我们联手的时机
It's a time for coming together.
好日子就快到来了
The salad days are fast approaching.
老挝那边进展顺利
Laos worked perfectly.
民众很快会投奔我们
Soon the populace will turn to us--
军队  财政  能源的首领们
the leaders of the military,
都会与我们为伍
finance and energy-- to right the ship.
然后
And then...
我们就能依我们的设想重建这个国家
we'll rebuild this country in our own image.
格雷琴  我希望那时你可以在我身边
And when we do, I want you there beside me, Gretchen.
如我许诺过的  做我的副手
As my number two, like I always promised.
丽莎呢
What about Lisa?
我已经跟你说了
I've already told you.
你才是我的女人
You're my girl.
出来
Come on.
去那边
Over there.
就站那儿
Right up there.
你和我都是同一类人
You and I are the same,
阿历克斯
Alex.
我做过的事
I've done things...
用力推
Push!
继续推  继续
Keep going, keep going!
Keep going! Keep going!
很好  就这样
Yeah, it's good right there.
够到了吗
You got it?
就这样
That's it.
我不知道这个能撑多久
I don't know how long that's going to hold.
我们只要把这个拉过去就行了
All we got to do is pull this thing through.
大家用力推
Oh, guys, push!
断了
Oh! It broke!
木桩断了
The brace is broke!
怀特先生
Mr. White...
很抱歉打扰你  我和莫拉侦探谈过后
I'm sorry to bother you, but, uh, after my talk
我一直在想布劳努先生
with Detective Mara, I was thinking about Mr. Blauner
和我之间的谈话
and some of the conversations we had.
推销员和渔夫很相似  不是吗
Salesmen are a lot like fishermen, right?
总是对自己的业绩夸夸其谈
Always bragging about their big catch.
但安迪却闭口不提他的业绩
Well, Andy never talked about his sales,
无论我如何旁敲侧击
No matter how much I pried.
所以我擅自查了一下
So I took the liberty of... looking them up.
表面  至少存在一些
And there were, to say the least...
不正常数据
irregularities.
安迪  下午好
Good afternoon to you, too, Andy.
你的2个大客户没有
Two of your top buyers don't have valid
合法社保号
Social Security numbers.
我查了那个他所谓的
I checked out the Social Security numbers
伽特工厂买主的社保号
of the clients he allegedly sold GATE workshops to.
有些纯粹是捏造的
In some cases the numbers are just pure fabrications.
但账务必须清算啊
But the checks must've cleared.
他之前肯定在洗钱
He's must've been money laundering for God only knows
天晓得用什么勾当
what kind of criminal exploits.
关键是
The point is...
如果那个执法长官拿到这份报告
if the good officer gets his hands on these papers, you know
你估计就得去见国税核对员了
you're going to be up to your eyeballs in IRS auditors.
我建议你跟莫拉先生说
I suggest you go tell Mr. Mara
你发现布劳努的帐有问题
that you found some irregularities in Blauner's expenses.
注销了私人物品  等等
Writing off personal matters, et cetera.
这就能解释他为会消失
This will explain why he disappeared
也可以息事宁人
and will placate the po-po.
好吧
Okay.
听着  侦探
Listen, Detective...
把它抬起来
Pick it up! Pick it up!
抬不起来  太重了
I can't, it's too heavy!
支柱肯定是断了
The brace must have snapped.
试试把它抬起来
Let's try and get it up!
根本动不了
It's not moving!
水来了
The water's coming.
水来了  出来
The water's coming! Come on!
我们只能把它留在那了
We got to leave it there.
这样就再也拿不到"锡拉"了
But then we'll never get Scylla.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
你没有  我有
You don't, I do.
你这是干嘛
What the hell are you doing?!
布拉德  别这样  布拉德
Brad, don't do this! Brad!
抓住它  快
Grab it, grab it, now!
水来了
The water's coming!
出来吧  快
Get your ass up here, now!
加把劲
Come on, come on!
你听到没有
You hear that?
他们往管子里注水了
They're flooding the pipe.
林肯  快出来
Linc! Get out of there!
太吵了  他听不到
It's too loud, he can't hear you!
林肯
Linc!
快点儿  你现在还能
Come on, man, there's still enough room
从洞里钻出来
for you to get through the hole.
我一放手你会抓不住的
I let go of this you could drop it.
它太重了
It's too heavy!
布拉德  放下管子
Brad, drop the sleeve
赶快出来
and get out of there!
别这么做
Don't do this.
你还有个儿子
You have a son!
别这么做  别这么做
Don't do this. Don't do this!
推  推吧  斯科菲尔德
Push it! Push it, Scofield!
快点  推过去
Come on,push it through!
推
Push!
推啊
Push it!
快推
Push it! Push it!
布拉德  布拉德  不
Brad! Brad, no!
布拉德
Brad!
布拉德  不
Brad, no!
布拉德
Brad! Brad!
Brad!
布拉德  不
Brad, no!
布拉德
Brad! Brad!
你们可以进来了
You can all come back in now.
一切正常
Everything's fine.
一向如此
It always was.
你还好吧
You're okay?
再好不过
Couldn't be better.
更重要的是  "锡拉"怎么样了
More important: what's happening with Scylla?
我会私下告诉你
I'll tell you in private.
你可以当着格雷琴的面告诉我
You can tell me in front of Gretchen.
等我说完一些话再说
Not until I say something else.
你要是再拿着枪靠近他
If you ever come near him with a gun again...
你会怎样
You'll what?
够了
That will do.
"锡拉"
Scylla.
我们安排保安就位的情况
We got preliminary safeguards in place
比预期的快
faster than we expected.
如果需要  我们明天就能转移"锡拉"
We could move Scylla tomorrow if we wanted,
但现在怀特已经除掉了斯科菲尔德和布伦斯
but now that Wyatt's eliminated Scofield and Burrows,
也就没必要了
there's no need.
斯科菲尔德和布伦斯死了
Scofield and Burrows are dead?
死了
Dead as Latin.
按原计划进行
Go ahead with the plan.
如果几个伊州小子
If a couple of boys from Illinois
都能这么接近  那就该重新布局了
could get that close, it's time to mix things up.
我要"锡拉"明天之内移出洛城
I want Scylla out of Los Angeles by the end of the day tomorrow.
他不肯爬上来
He wouldn't climb up.
他就是不肯爬上来
He just wouldn't climb up.
南边的管子通到哪儿
Where does the south pipe lead to?
-或者我们可以沿着它  -不
Maybe we can follow... No.
不  他死了
No, he's gone.